marketamerica.com 2019-05-21

# Market America - Built on Product Powered by People - Market America

This Privacy Policy applies to this website and all Market America Worldwide websites (collectively the "Site") and mobile applications (collectively the "Mobile App"). The Site and Mobile App are owned and operated by Market America, Inc. ("Market America").

 **We appreciate the trust you've placed in us, and we want you to know what information we collect from you and how we use and share it. By vising the Site or using a Mobile App, you accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy.**

 **We work closely with Shop MA, Inc., SHOP.com Marketplace, Inc., Market America, Inc. and each of their various subsidiaries and affiliated companies (collectively the "Affiliates"), and your personal, technical and discretionary information may be shared with each of these Affiliates, in the discretion of Market America, Inc. For this reason, throughout these Terms, references made to "Market America" "MA" "Company" "we" "us" and "our" collectively include Market America, Inc. and the Affiliates. The Site is hosted in the United States.**

## Information We Collect

We collect and store information you provide to us through the Site and the Mobile App.

  1. ### Personal Information

The information we collect may include, without limitation, your name, address, telephone number, email address, corporate information, testimonial, and date of birth. Personal information will be collected at various times including, without limitation, when you:

    * Write an e-mail or letter to Market America
    * Submit a product review or testimonial to Market America
    * Participate in a marketing survey, promotion or event
    * Contact our customer service or product information departments
    * Register on our Site
    * Navigate the Site
  2. ### Technical information we collect and store automatically

Whenever you visit the Site, we automatically collect and store the following information: the Internet address from which you accessed the Site, the date and time you visited the Site, the duration of your visit to the Site, whether you are a new or returning visitor, the page from which you exit the Site, what country you are visiting from (your network location), the Internet address of the web site from which you linked to the Site, the name of the file or words you searched for, items clicked on a page, information about your mobile device including the unique identifier for your device and the browser and operating system used. The Site is not designed to respond to "do not track" requests from browsers.

  3. ### Cookies

This information is stored using session ID cookies, persistent cookies and various other types of cookies. A cookie is a small data file that is stored by your web browser on your computer.

  4. ### Third party Information

To help us understand and enhance our interactions with you, we may permit web analytics and other providers to collect and process information on our Site using the technologies described above. Some of these providers have information about you, including personal information, demographic information and interest reports which they will share with us. And we may share your personal and technical information with them.

## Using Information We Collect

We want to provide you with the best possible internet experience and fulfill your orders exactly as you've requested. Additionally, we want to make your experience with Market America a pleasant and positive one. In order to do this, we may use any information we collect for any legitimate business purpose (including, but not limited to, marketing). For example, we may use the information as follows:

  1. ### Use of Personal Information

    * Match you with the Shop Consultant that is the best possible fit for you;
    * Send you promotional offers;
    * Identify your product and service preferences;
    * Customize our communications to you;
    * Improve our customer service;
    * Share your positive product testimonial with others;
    * Include your name, stories, testimonials, product reviews and images in Market America and third party publications, literature and/or other media, on Market America operated websites, on third party websites, at Market America events, on Market America CDs and DVDs, in any other Market America communications to our UnFranchise Owners, partner stores, third party service providers or others, or as otherwise deemed useful or appropriate by Market America.
  2. ### Use of Technical Information

This information is used to measure the number of visitors to the Site and to various sections of the Site, the percentage of visits that came from particular key word searches, the average time spent on the Site by visitors, and the average number of page views by visitors. It may also be used to identify system performance or problem areas. We also use this information to help us improve the Site, analyze patterns of usage, and to make the Site more useful. This information is not used for associating search terms or patterns of site navigation with individual users. The Site may periodically delete its web logs. We use third party analytics services to collect and analyze this data, and on occasion, we may provide this information to third party entities we contract with for the purpose of further analyzing website traffic.

  3. ### Use of Cookies

Cookies allow us to enhance, personalize and track your online experience, so that the information you receive is more relevant to you. This technology will allow you to move faster through our website once the information is in our database since you do not have to re-enter the same information or log in each time you enter the site.

  4. ### Third party Information

Third Party Information helps us to enhance and personalize our interactions with you so that the information you receive is more relevant to you. We use third party information for behavioral advertising, which allows us to predict your preferences in order to show you ads and send you e-mails that are more likely to interest you.

## Information We Share with Others and Your Privacy Rights

It is not a practice of Market America to sell, rent, or trade personal information. In order to best service our customers and Preferred Customers, we may share any information we collect for any legitimate business purpose. For example, when we share your order information, we share some of your personal information and information about your spending habits with the Market America Independent UnFranchise Owner ("UnFranchise Owner") assigned as your Shop Consultant. UnFranchise Owners are obligated to treat the information you supply with confidentiality.

We share certain limited information with the partner stores where you shop. We may also share your personal and technical information with web analytics companies and services in order to provide a more personalized web experience for you.

We use third party service providers to help us operate our business, the Site and the Mobile App, provide certain services or administer activities on our behalf, such as credit card processing, sending emails, shipping orders, printing, web design and hosting, public and media relations, internet services, e-commerce, order fulfillment and contest/sweepstakes administration. We will share your information with these third parties for those purposes. For example, whenever you place an order through the Site, we will provide your name, address, phone numbers and other information required by the shipper so that the shipper can efficiently deliver your order according to their internal and legal requirements.

If we offer sweepstakes, contests and/or similar promotions through the Site we will ask you for certain personally identifiable information when you enter and if you win. We will share this personally identifiable information with the third party sponsors of such sweepstakes, contests and promotions (irrespective of whether it is hosted by us) or others, in accordance with the rules for such sweepstakes, contest or promotion. You should carefully review the rules for each sweepstakes, contest and promotion offered through the Site before you participate, as they may contain additional information about the use of your personally identifiable information by us or the sponsor. If there is a conflict between the rules concerning the treatment of your personally identifiable information and this Privacy Policy, the rules shall control.

On rare occasions, we may disclose specific information upon governmental request, in response to a court order, or when required by law to do so. We may also share information with companies assisting in fraud protection or investigation. We do not provide information to these agencies or companies for marketing or commercial purposes.

## How We Use Email

When you provide us your email address, you may receive emails from us, and/or from your UnFranchise Owner. E-mails may be sent in order to assist us in processing your order, respond to a request, provide customer service or inform you about products, services or promotional materials. It is our intent to send promotional e-mails only to those persons who wish to receive them. We provide instructions on how to unsubscribe in our e-mails.

## Links to Other Sites

From time to time, we provide links to third party sites on the Site and the Mobile App. These sites operate independently of Market America and have established their own privacy and security policies. We encourage you to review these policies at any site you visit.

## Updating or Reviewing Your Information

You may review or update your customer or Preferred Customer information (name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, credit card number, etc.) under Your Account.

## Security

Market America is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. It is our intent to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you. We use a variety of current technologies and processes for protection of information we collect, and we limit the information we provide to third parties.

When you make a purchase or submit a document on the Site, your transactional information is transmitted in a safe, encrypted format.

## Privacy of Children on Our Site

The Site and Mobile App are not intended for use by anyone under the legal age. We are committed to protecting children's privacy on the Internet and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

## Your Consent

By using and continuing to use the Site or the Mobile App, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information as detailed in this privacy policy.

## Privacy Policy, Terms of Use, Notices and Revisions

Your use of the Site and the Mobile App, and any disputes arising from such use, are subject to this Privacy Policy as well as our Terms of Service and all of its dispute resolution provisions, including, but not limited to, the provisions addressing limitation on damages and choice of law. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service at any time. All changes and clarifications will take effect immediately, upon their posting on this Site. If we make changes, we will post them and indicate the most recent revision date of this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to refer to this policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy applies to this Site.

## Contact Us

We always welcome your questions and feedback. For privacy-related issues, please contact us at privacy@marketamerica.com.
